Guide to the Duke University Living History Program records, 1973-2005 and undated UA.22.02.0001
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Interviews, 1973-2005 and undated; 1
  - Duke, Angier Biddle, 1990 October 24; 17
    - Original VHS Video-cassette, 1990 October 24 (Box 17, Video-cassette UA.22.02.0001-VHS-0093)
      Duke University Living History Program presents A Conversation Angier Biddle Duke; former United States Ambassador; also Robin Duke; October 24, 1990; Tape two: 1:30:00
    - Original VHS Video-cassette, 1990 October 24 (Box 17, Video-cassette UA.22.02.0001-VHS-0094)
      Duke University Living History Program presents A Conversation Angier Biddle Duke; former United States Ambassador; also Robin Duke; October 24, 1990; Tape three 57:49
    - Original VHS Video-cassette, 1990 October 24 (Box 17, Video-cassette UA.22.02.0001-VHS-0095)
    - Original VHS Video-cassette, 1990 October 24 (Box 17, Video-cassette UA.22.02.0001-VHS-0096)
    - Original VHS Video-cassette, 1990 October 24 (Box 17, Video-cassette UA.22.02.0001-VHS-0097)
    - Original VHS Video-cassette, 1990 October 24 (Box 17, Video-cassette UA.22.02.0001-VHS-0098)
    - Transcript (3 copies), undated; 3 folders (Box 25)
  - Fulbright, J. William, 1983 September 22; 18
    - Original Video-cassette, 1983 September 22 (Box 19, Video-cassette UA.22.02.0001-Umatic-0153)
      Living History; Sen. J. Wm. Fulbright; 9/22/83/ Reel #2
    - Original Video-cassette, 1983 September 23 (Box 19, Video-cassette UA.22.02.0001-Umatic-0154)
      Living History; Senator Fulbright; 9/23/83; Reel #3
    - Original Video-cassette, 1983 September 23 (Box 19, Video-cassette UA.22.02.0001-Umatic-0155)
      Living History; Senator Fulbright; 9/23/83; Reel #4
    - Original 1-inch Video-reel, 1983 September 22 (Box 1, Video-reel UA.22.02.0001-Vid1-0001)
      Duke Living History Program; Senator J. William Fullbright; September 22, 1983, Reel #1; Original
    - Original 1-inch Video-reel, 1983 September 22 (Video-reel UA.22.02.0001-Vid1-0002)
      Duke Living History Program; Senator J. William Fullbright; September 22, 1983, Reel #2; Original
    - Original 1-inch Video-reel, 1983 September 22 (Video-reel UA.22.02.0001-Vid1-0003)
      Duke Living History Program; Senator J. William Fullbright; September 22, 1983, Reel #3; Original
    - Original 1-inch Video-reel, 1983 September 22 (Video-reel UA.22.02.0001-Vid1-0004)
      Duke Living History Program; Senator J. William Fullbright; September 22, 1983, Reel #4; Original
    - Original 3/4-inch Video-cassette, 1983 September 22 (Box 19, Video-cassette UA.22.02.0001-Umatic-0152)
      Duke University Living History Program; Senator J. William Fulbright; September 22, 1983; Reel #1; 3/4" Back-up
    - Transcript, 1983 (Box 25)
    - Transcript (3 copies), 1983; 3 folders (Box 26)
      see also: Israel / AIPAC Lobby: Vietnam: 3 Perspectives; Misinformation In Crisis Management
  - Gaidar, Yegor T., 2000 January 21; 19
    - Original betacam-sp Video-cassette, 2000 January 21 (Box 22, Video-cassette UA.22.02.001-Bcam-0063)
      Duke Living History Program Interview with Yegor Gaidar; 1/21/00; Director - S. Wells; TD - T. Wilson; Audio - S. Smith; Cameras - K. Karavatos, M. Kitchens; Ch 1 - Gaidar; Ch 2 - Panel; TRT 55:50; Original Master
    - Original VHS Video-cassette, 2000 January 21 (Box 17, Video-cassette UA.22.02.0001-VHS-0099)
      The Duke University Living History Program presents An Interview with Yegor T. Gaidar; Chairman, Democratic Choice party of Russia; 1st Post-Soviet Prime Minister in Russia; January 21, 2000; TRT 55:50
    - Original VHS Video-cassette, 2000 January 21 (Box 17, Video-cassette UA.22.02.0001-VHS-0100)
  - Gergen, David, 1999 October 22; 20
    - Original betacam-sp Video-cassette, 1999 October 22 (Box 22, Video-cassette UA.22.02.001-Bcam-0064)
      Living History; 10/22/99; Ch 1 - David Gergen; Ch 2 - moderator; TRT 1:01:00
    - Original VHS Video-cassette, 1999 October 22 (Box 16, Video-cassette UA.22.02.0001-VHS-0063)
      The Duke University Living History Program presents A Conversation with David Gergen; October 22, 1999; Duke Recording Studios; TRT- 1:03:00
    - Original VHS Video-cassette, 1999 October 22 (Box 16, Video-cassette UA.22.02.0001-VHS-0064)
  - Goldstone, Richard Judge, 1997 October 20; 21
    - Original betacam-sp Video-cassette, 1997 October 20 (Box 21, Video-cassette UA.22.02.001-Bcam-0054)
      Duke University Living History Program presents A Conversation with Judge Richard Goldstone; Justice of the Constitutional Court of South Africa; october 20, 1997; part one - 1:25:03; Part Two - 1:13:04; Tape One; Master
    - Original betacam-sp Video-cassette, 1997 October 20 (Box 21, Video-cassette UA.22.02.001-Bcam-0055)
      Duke University Living History Program presents A Conversation with Judge Richard Goldstone; Justice of the Constitutional Court of South Africa; october 20, 1997; part one - 1:25:03; Part Two - 1:13:04; Tape Two; Master
    - Original VHS Video-cassette, 1997 October 20 (Box 16, Video-cassette UA.22.02.0001-VHS-0066)
      Duke University Living History Program presents A Conversation with Judge Richard Goldstone; Justice of the Constitutional Court of South Africa; october 20, 1997; part one - 1:25:03; Part Two - 1:13:04; Tape One
    - Original VHS Video-cassette, 1997 October 20 (Box 16, Video-cassette UA.22.02.0001-VHS-0067)
      Duke University Living History Program presents A Conversation with Judge Richard Goldstone; Justice of the Constitutional Court of South Africa; october 20, 1997; part one - 1:25:03; Part Two - 1:13:04; Tape Two
    - Original VHS Video-cassette, 1997 October 20 (Box 16, Video-cassette UA.22.02.0001-VHS-0068)
    - Original VHS Video-cassette, 1997 October 20 (Box 16, Video-cassette UA.22.02.0001-VHS-0069)
    - Transcript (4 copies), undated; 4 folders (Box 26)
  - Gourevitch, Philip, 1999 March 30; 22
    - Original betacam-sp Video-cassette, 1999 March 29 (Box 22, Video-cassette UA.22.02.001-Bcam-0066)
      Living History Shoot; 3/29/99; Philip Gourevitch; Split Audio; Master
    - Original VHS Video-cassette, 1999 March 30 (Box 16, Video-cassette UA.22.02.0001-VHS-0070)
      The Duke University Living History Program presents A Conversation with Philip Gourevitch; March 30, 1999; Duke Recording Studios; TRT- 38:00
    - Original VHS Video-cassette, 1999 March 30 (Box 16, Video-cassette UA.22.02.0001-VHS-0071)
  - Griffis, Stanton, 1974 May 4; 23
    - Original 3/4-inch Video-cassette, 1974 May 4 (Box 4, Video-cassette UA.22.02.0001-Umatic-0043)
      Griffis, W. Stanton; Interview May 4, 1974; Circa 60 minutes re his services in Spain Argentina, Sweden, Poland, Egypt, etc.; Master
    - Transcript, 1974 (Box 26)
  - Griffis, Stanton and Smith, Earl E.T., 1974 and undated; 24
    - Original 3/4-inch Video-cassette, undated (Box 19, Video-cassette UA.22.02.0001-Umatic-0150)
      Amb. Earl E.T. Smith - Cuba; Amb Stanton Griffis - Spain - Argentin; OSS Mission to Sweden for FDR
    - Original 3/4-inch Video-cassette, 1974 May 4 (Box 4, Video-cassette UA.22.02.0001-Umatic-0042)
      Griffis, W. Stanton; Circa 1/4 hour of original interview, May 4, 1974; Smith Earl E.T.; Circa 5 minutes of original interview May 4, 1974; Master
  - Harriman, W. Averell, 1977 and undated; 25
    - Original 3/4-inch Video-cassette, undated (Box 19, Video-cassette UA.22.02.0001-Umatic-0151)
      Duke University; Rutherford A-V project; perkins Lib.' Gov. Harriman - Elie Abel - Amb. Duke; 90 min; use copy
    - Original 3/4-inch Video-cassette, 1977 July 21 (Box 7, Video-cassette UA.22.02.0001-Umatic-0045)
      Gov. W. Averell Harriman conversation with Ellie Able and Amb. Angier Biddle Duke for the Jay Ruthor Audio-Visual History Porject of the W. R. Perkins Library at Duke University
    - Transcript (2 copies), 1977; 2 folders (Box 26)
  - Harriman, W. Averell; Smith, Earl E. T.; Clay, Lucius; Griffis, Stanton, undated; 26
    - Original 3/4-inch Video-cassette, undated (Box 7, Video-cassette UA.22.02.0001-Umatic-0044)
      Duke Univ. Rutherford A-V project - Perkins Library; 1st Copy; Demo; Edited; Rutherford; Intro - Gov. Harriman, Amb. Earl Smith, Gen. Clay - Amb. Griffis; Approx :17; Master
  - Hoffman, Abbie, 1988 and undated; 27
    - Original 3/4-inch Video-cassette, 1988 April 6 (Box 7, Video-cassette UA.22.02.0001-Umatic-0046)
      Abbie Hoffman; Tape 1; 4/6/88
    - Original 3/4-inch Video-cassette, 1988 April 6 (Box 7, Video-cassette UA.22.02.0001-Umatic-0047)
      Abbie Hoffman; 4/6/88; Page Auditorium; tape 2; No time code
    - Original VHS Video-cassette, undated (Box 16, Video-cassette UA.22.02.0001-VHS-0065)
      Abbie Hoffman Dub; view copy
  - Israel/AIPAC Lobby excerpts from Fulbright/Percy, undated; 28
    - Transcript, undated (Box 26)
  - Jackson, Jesse, 1988-1993 and undated; 29
    - Original 3/4-inch Video-cassette, 1988 August 28 (Box 7, Video-cassette UA.22.02.0001-Umatic-0048)
      Tape 1: "American Dream"; J. Jackson Intro.
    - Original 3/4-inch Video-cassette, 1988 August 28 (Box 7, Video-cassette UA.22.02.0001-Umatic-0049)
      Tape 2: Jackson Speech, Beginning
    - Original 3/4-inch Video-cassette, 1988 August 28 (Box 7, Video-cassette UA.22.02.0001-Umatic-0050)
      Tape 3: Jackson, End. Includes some of voter registration
    - Original betacam-sp Video-cassette, 1993 March 9 (Box 6, Video-cassette UA.22.02.0001-Bcam-0014)
      Jesse Jackson; Living History; Tape 1 of 2; 1 + 3 - Jackson; 2 + 4 - panel; Time 59:34; Master
    - Original betacam-sp Video-cassette, 1993 March 9 (Box 6, Video-cassette UA.22.02.0001-Bcam-0015)
      Jesse Jackson; Living History; 2 of 2; 1 + 3 Jackson; 2 + 4 panel; 3/9/93; time 37:06; Master
    - Original VHS Video-cassette, undated (Box 5, Video-cassette UA.22.02.0001-VHS-0005)
      Jesse Jackson; Living History
    - Original VHS Video-cassette, 1993 March 9 (Box 16, Video-cassette UA.22.02.0001-VHS-0060)
      Duke University Living History Program presents; A Conversation with Jesse Jackson; March 9, 1993; Part One 59:34
    - Original VHS Video-cassette, 1993 March 9 (Box 16, Video-cassette UA.22.02.0001-VHS-0061)
      Duke University Living History Program presents; A Conversation with Jesse Jackson; March 9, 1993; Part Two 37:06
    - Transcript, undated (Box 26)
  - Jordan, Robert W., 2002 February 18; 30
    - Original betacam-sp Video-cassette, 2002 February 18 (Box 22, Video-cassette UA.22.02.001-Bcam-0060)
      Duke Living History; Interview with Ambassador Robert W. Jordan; US Ambassador to Saudi Arabia; 2/18/02/ 8:30-10 Duke Recording Studio; Ch. 1. Jordan; Ch. 2 - Subbing, Bliwise; TRT 1:00:30
    - Original VHS Video-cassette, 2002 February 18 (Box 17, Video-cassette UA.22.02.0001-VHS-0108)
      Duke University Living History Program Presents; A Conversation with Robert Jordan; US Ambassador to Saudi Arabia; recorded on February 18, 2002
  - Kaplan, Rick, 2004 March 24; 31
    - Original betacam-sp Video-cassette, 2004 March 24 (Box 22, Video-cassette UA.22.02.001-Bcam-0059)
      Living History; 3/24/04; with Rick Kaplan MSNBC; with Susan Tifft Sanford Institute; TRT 1:08:17; Titles Added; 5/20/04
    - Original VHS Video-cassette, 2004 March 24 (Box 17, Video-cassette UA.22.02.0001-VHS-0107)
      Duke University Living History Program Presents; A Conversation with Rick Kaplan; President of MSNBC; recorded on March 24, 2004
  - King Michael of Romania, 1991; 32
    - Original betacam-sp Video-cassette, 1991 February 11 (Box 9, Video-cassette UA.22.02.0001-Bcam-0025)
      King, Michael; 2/11/91; Part I; ISO Machine; 1 King; 2 Panel; 3 King; 4 Panel
    - Original betacam-sp Video-cassette, 1991 February 11 (Box 9, Video-cassette UA.22.02.0001-Bcam-0026)
      King, Michael; 2/11/91; Part II; ISO Machine; 1 King; 2 Panel; 3 King; 4 Panel
    - Original betacam-sp Video-cassette, 1991 February 12 (Box 9, Video-cassette UA.22.02.0001-Bcam-0027)
      Duke Living History; King Michael of Romania; ISO Reel #3; 2/12/91
    - Original betacam-sp Video-cassette, 1991 February 12 (Box 9, Video-cassette UA.22.02.0001-Bcam-0028)
      Duke Living History; King Michael of Romania; ISO Reel #4; 2/12/91
    - Original betacam-sp Video-cassette, 1991 February 11 (Box 9, Video-cassette UA.22.02.0001-Bcam-0029)
      Duke Living History; King Michael of Romania; Prg. Reel 1; 2/11/91; 57:00
    - Original betacam-sp Video-cassette, 1991 February 11 (Box 9, Video-cassette UA.22.02.0001-Bcam-0030)
      King, Michael; 2/11/91; Living History Part II; program; 1-King; 2-Panel; 3-King; 4-Panel; 58:30
    - Original betacam-sp Video-cassette, 1991 February 12 (Box 9, Video-cassette UA.22.02.0001-Bcam-0031)
      Duke Living History; King Michael of Romania; Prg. Reel 3; 2/12/91; 59:30
    - Original betacam-sp Video-cassette, 1991 February 12 (Box 9, Video-cassette UA.22.02.0001-Bcam-0032)
      Duke Living History; King Michael of Romania; Prg. Reel 4; 2/12/91; 60:00
  - Lewis, Samuel, 1992 October 15; 33
    - Original Video-cassette, 1992 October 15 (Box 17, Video-cassette UA.22.02.0001-VHS-0102)
      Duke University Living History Program presents A Conversation with Samuel Lewis; former U.S. Ambassador to Israel; October 15, 1992; Part Two 1:06:22
    - Original betacam-sp Video-cassette, 1992 October 15 (Box 6, Video-cassette UA.22.02.0001-Bcam-0016)
      10/15 Samuel Lewis; Living History; 1 of 2; 1 + 3- Lewis; 2 + 4 - Panel; TC in: 00:00:38:00; TC Out: 1:23:53:00; Duration: 1:23:15:00
    - Original betacam-sp Video-cassette, 1992 October 15 (Box 6, Video-cassette UA.22.02.0001-Bcam-0017)
      10/15 Samuel Lewis; Living History; 2 of 2; 1 + 3- Lewis; 2 + 4 - Panel; TC in: 00:01:25:16:05; TC Out: 02:31:38:25; Duration: 1:06:22:20
    - Original betacam-sp Video-cassette, 1992 October 15 (Box 6, Video-cassette UA.22.02.0001-Bcam-0018)
      Duke University Living History; Samuel Lewis; 10-15-92; Edit Master for dubbing; TC In: 00:00:38:00; TC Out: 012:23:52:00; Duration 1:23:15:00; Master
    - Original VHS Video-cassette, 1992 October 15 (Box 17, Video-cassette UA.22.02.0001-VHS-0101)
      Duke University Living History Program presents A Conversation with Samuel Lewis; former U.S. Ambassador to Israel; October 15, 1992; Part One 1:23:15
    - Transcript (3 copies), 1992 (Box 26)
  - Luers, William, 1995 March 22; 34
    - Original betacam-sp Video-cassette, 1995 March 22 (Box 6, Video-cassette UA.22.02.0001-Bcam-0019)
      Luers 1; 3/22/95/ Living History; 1 + 3 - Askers; 2 + 4 - Telhers; 59:20 w/ titles
    - Original betacam-sp Video-cassette, 1995 March 22 (Box 6, Video-cassette UA.22.02.0001-Bcam-0020)
      Luers 2; 3/22/95; Living History; 1 + 3 panel; 2 + 4 guests; with his wife Wendy Woods Turnbull 1:24:35
    - Original VHS Video-cassette, 1995 March 22 (Box 16, Video-cassette UA.22.02.0001-VHS-0072)
      The Duke University Living History Program presents A Conversation with William Luers; March 22, 1995; Tape One - 59:20
    - Original VHS Video-cassette, 1995 March 22 (Box 16, Video-cassette UA.22.02.0001-VHS-0073)
      The Duke University Living History Program presents A Conversation with William Luers; Former Unites States Ambassador and Wendy Woods Turnbull (Ambassador Luer's Wive); March 22, 1995; Tape Two - 1:24:35
    - Original VHS Video-cassette, 1995 March 22 (Box 16, Video-cassette UA.22.02.0001-VHS-0074)
    - Original VHS Video-cassette, 1995 March 22 (Box 16, Video-cassette UA.22.02.0001-VHS-0075)
  - Lyman, Princeton, 2001 October 17; 35
    - Original betacam-sp Video-cassette, 2001 October 17 (Box 22, Video-cassette UA.22.02.001-Bcam-0061)
      Duke Living History Program; Princeton Lyman; former US Ambassador to S. Africa and Nigeria; with Bruce Jentleson; 10/17/01; mixed mono; TRT 44:27; Master
    - Original VHS Video-cassette, 2001 October 17 (Box 17, Video-cassette UA.22.02.0001-VHS-0106)
      Duke University Living History Program Presents; A Conversation with Princeton Lyman; former US Ambassador to South Africa and Nigeria; recorded on October 17, 2001
  - Madrid Huratado, Miguel de la, 1996 April 9; 36
    - Original betacam-sp Video-cassette, 1996 April 9 (Box 21, Video-cassette UA.22.02.001-Bcam-0052)
      De La Madrid; Living History; Tape #1; 4/9/96; original; Run time: 58:23; Title Added 9/23/96; Master
    - Original betacam-sp Video-cassette, 1996 April 9 (Box 21, Video-cassette UA.22.02.001-Bcam-0053)
      De La Madrid; Living History; Tape #2; 4/9/96; original; Run time: 51:28; Title Added 9/23/96; Master
    - Original VHS Video-cassette, 1996 April 9 (Box 17, Video-cassette UA.22.02.0001-VHS-0084)
      Duke University Living History Program presents A Conversation with Miguel de la Madrid; former president of Mexico; Part one - 58:23; Part Two - 51:28; Part One
    - Original VHS Video-cassette, 1996 April 9 (Box 17, Video-cassette UA.22.02.0001-VHS-0085)
      Duke University Living History Program presents A Conversation with Miguel de la Madrid; former president of Mexico; Part one - 58:23; Part Two - 51:28; Part Two
    - Original VHS Video-cassette, 1996 April 9 (Box 17, Video-cassette UA.22.02.0001-VHS-0086)
    - Original VHS Video-cassette, 1996 April 9 (Box 17, Video-cassette UA.22.02.0001-VHS-0087)
    - Original VHS Video-cassette, 1996 April 9 (Box 17, Video-cassette UA.22.02.0001-VHS-0088)
    - Original VHS Video-cassette, 1996 April 9 (Box 17, Video-cassette UA.22.02.0001-VHS-0089)
    - Original VHS Video-cassette, 1996 April 9 (Box 17, Video-cassette UA.22.02.0001-VHS-0090)
    - Transcript (3 copies), 1996 (Box 26)
  - Magelov, Mikhail, 1999 March 30; 37
    - Original VHS Video-cassette, 1999 March 30 (Box 5, Video-cassette UA.22.02.0001-VHS-0019)
      The Living History program of duke University presents a conversation with Mikhail Magelov; 3/30/1999; duke Recording Studios; TRT - 39:00
    - Original VHS Video-cassette, 1999 March 30 (Box 5, Video-cassette UA.22.02.0001-VHS-0020)
    - Original betacam-sp Video-cassette, 1999 March 30 (Box 22, Video-cassette UA.22.02.001-Bcam-0067)
      Living History; Mikhail Margelov; 3/30/99; Split Track Audio; Master
  - Matlock, Jack F., 1997-1989 and undated; 38
    - Original 3/4-inch Video-cassette, 1989 March 24 (Box 7, Video-cassette UA.22.02.0001-Umatic-0051)
      Guest: James Matlock; Panelists: Warren Lerner, Martin Miller, Thomas Naylor; Director: Charles Newman; length 53:56; reel 1/2
    - Original 3/4-inch Video-cassette, 1989 March 24 (Box 7, Video-cassette UA.22.02.0001-Umatic-0052)
      Guest: James Matlock; Panelists: Warren Lerner, Martin Miller, Thomas Naylor; Director: Charles Newman; length 48:02; Reel 2/2
    - Original 3/4-inch Video-cassette, undated (Box 7, Video-cassette UA.22.02.0001-Umatic-0053)
      ISO 1; cam 2; Matlock
    - Original 3/4-inch Video-cassette, undated (Box 7, Video-cassette UA.22.02.0001-Umatic-0054)
      ISO 2; Matlock
    - Original betacam-sp Video-cassette, 1997 April 3 (Box 21, Video-cassette UA.22.02.001-Bcam-0046)
      Duke University Living History Program Presents A Conversation with Jack Matlock; Former United States Ambassador to the Soviet Union; April 3, 1997; Part One-42:48; Part Two-45:10; Part One
    - Original betacam-sp Video-cassette, 1997 April 3 (Box 21, Video-cassette UA.22.02.001-Bcam-0047)
    - Original VHS Video-cassette, 1997 April 3 (Box 16, Video-cassette UA.22.02.0001-VHS-0044)
    - Original VHS Video-cassette, 1997 April 3 (Box 16, Video-cassette UA.22.02.0001-VHS-0045)
      Duke University Living History Program Presents A Conversation with Jack Matlock; Former United States Ambassador to the Soviet Union; April 3, 1997; Part One-42:48; Part Two-45:10; Part Two
    - Original VHS Video-cassette, 1997 April 3 (Box 16, Video-cassette UA.22.02.0001-VHS-0046)
    - Original VHS Video-cassette, 1997 April 3 (Box 16, Video-cassette UA.22.02.0001-VHS-0047)
    - Original VHS Video-cassette, 1989 April 7 (Box 16, Video-cassette UA.22.02.0001-VHS-0048)
      Duke University Living History Program Presents A Conversation with Jack Matlock; Former United States Ambassador to the Soviet Union; April 7, 1989; VHS duplicate
    - Original VHS Video-cassette, 1989 April 7 (Box 16, Video-cassette UA.22.02.0001-VHS-0049)
    - Transcript, undated (Box 26)
    - Transcript (2 copies), 1998 (Box 26)
  - McGhee, George, 1991 February 22; 39
    - Original betacam-sp Video-cassette, 1991 February 22 (Box 6, Video-cassette UA.22.02.0001-Bcam-0021)
      Duke Living History; McGhee; Panel - ch 1/3; Mc - ch. 2/4; Tape one; 53:00; program reel
    - Original betacam-sp Video-cassette, 1991 February 22 (Box 6, Video-cassette UA.22.02.0001-Bcam-0022)
      Duke Living History; McGhee; Panel - ch 1/3; Mc - ch. 2/4; Tape two; 53:00; program
    - Original betacam-sp Video-cassette, 1991 February 22 (Box 6, Video-cassette UA.22.02.0001-Bcam-0023)
      Duke Living History; McGhee; 2-22-91; tape one ISO
    - Original betacam-sp Video-cassette, 1991 February 22 (Box 7, Video-cassette UA.22.02.0001-Bcam-0024)
      Duke Living History; McGhee; 2-22-91; tape two ISO
    - Original VHS Video-cassette, 1991 February 22 (Box 5, Video-cassette UA.22.02.0001-VHS-0026)
      Duke University Living History Program presents; A Conversation with George McGhee; Former United States Ambassador; February 22, 1991; Part one - 53:00; Part Two-60:00
    - Original VHS Video-cassette, 1991 February 22 (Box 5, Video-cassette UA.22.02.0001-VHS-0027)
    - Original VHS Video-cassette, 1991 February 22 (Box 16, Video-cassette UA.22.02.0001-VHS-0050)
    - Transcript (2 copies), undated (Box 26)
  - McNamara, Robert S., 1986-1987 and undated; 40
    - Original 3/4-inch Video-cassette, undated (Box 8, Video-cassette UA.22.02.0001-Umatic-0055)
      Living History; Robert S. McNamara; 1986 Terry Sanford Lecturer; Edit Master: Reel II
    - Original 3/4-inch Video-cassette, undated (Box 8, Video-cassette UA.22.02.0001-Umatic-0056)
    - Original 3/4-inch Video-cassette, 1986 October 16 (Box 20, Video-cassette UA.22.02.0001-Umatic-0162)
      Duke University Living History Program; Robert S. McNamara; 1986 Terry Sanford Lecturer; Interviewed by: Dr. Ole R. Holsti, Dr. Timothy Lomperis, Dr. James r. Leutze; Camera Original: October 16, 1986; Camera 2/Tape 2
    - Original 3/4-inch Video-cassette, 1986 October 16 (Box 20, Video-cassette UA.22.02.0001-Umatic-0163)
      Duke University Living History Program; Robert S. McNamara; 1986 Terry Sanford Lecturer; Interviewed by: Dr. Ole R. Holsti, Dr. Timothy Lomperis, Dr. James r. Leutze; Camera Original: October 16, 1986; Camera 3/Tape 2
    - Original 3/4-inch Video-cassette, undated (Box 20, Video-cassette UA.22.02.0001-Umatic-0164)
      Living History; McNamara; Work Edit Master; Reel #1
    - Original VHS Video-cassette, 1986 October 16; 1987 August 27 (Box 5, Video-cassette UA.22.02.0001-VHS-0006)
      Robert S. McNamara; interviewed 10/16/86; dubbed 8/27/87; this tape contains segments 1 & 2; total run time approx = 1 hr. 40
    - Original VHS Video-cassette, 1987 August (Box 5, Video-cassette UA.22.02.0001-VHS-0007)
      Duke Living History Program presents; Robert S. McNamara; Interviewed 10/16/86; dubbed 8/87; this tape contains sebments 1 & 2 approx 1 hour 40 minutes
    - Transcript (3 copies), 1986 (Box 26)
      see also: Cuban Missile Crisis and Misinformation in Crisis
  - Mihai, King Michael of Romania, 1991 February 11; 41
    - Original VHS Video-cassette, 1991 February 11 (Box 5, Video-cassette UA.22.02.0001-VHS-0034)
      Duke University Living History Program Presents A Conversation with King Mihai of Romania; February 11, 1991; Use Copy; Tape One; Part One 57:00; Part Two 58:30
    - Original VHS Video-cassette, 1991 February 11 (Box 5, Video-cassette UA.22.02.0001-VHS-0035)